Finding Aid for Matthaei Botanical Gardens (University of Michigan) records, 1905-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical Files
  - 1914-2002
    - Benninghoff, Dr. W. S., 1986 (Box 6)
      (Address given by Patricia Hopkinson upon his retirement)
    - Biological Station, 1982-1986 (Box 6)
    - Birds at the Matthaei Botanical Gardens (Box 6)
    - Botanical Gardens in U.S., undated (Box 6)
    - Buildings and Grounds
      - Blueprints
        - 1914-1920, 2 folders (Box 6)
        - 1958-1965, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Buildings, 1966-1970 (Box 6)
      - Land Purchases, 1907-1931 (Box 6)
      - Eichstedt & Johnson, 1960-1961 (Box 6)
        (landscape architects)
      - Miscellaneous, 1930-1933 (Box 6)
    - Butterflies at Matthaei Botanical Gardens, undated (Box 7)
    - Collecting and Importing Permits, 1931-1934 (Box 7)
    - Dedication, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Dedication of Norman Memorial, 1987 (Box 7)
      (see also Photographs series)
    - Dixboro Site
      - Design Concept Report, 1960 (Box 7)
      - History (index cards), undated (Box 7)
      - Maps (Box 7)
      - Zoning Change, 1978 (Box 7)
    - Docents, 1983-1986 (Box 7)
    - Environmental Chambers, 1979-1986 (Box 7)
    - Ethnobotanical Trail Signs, c. late, 1990s (Box 7)
    - Events and Exhibits
      - Commemorative Garden Dedications, 1991-1997 (Box 7)
      - Matthaei By Moonlight, 2001-2003; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Michigan's Plants in Danger, 1980-1981 (Box 7)
      - Out of Africa, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Fleming Creek System, 1968-1976 (Box 7)
    - Flora and Fauna
      - 1958-1971 (Box 7)
      - List of Plants, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Floristic Survey, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Flower Shows
      - 1986-1987 (Box 7)
      - Flower Show, 1990
        - Planning Stages, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
        - 1988-1990 (Box 7)
    - Foreign Plant Introductions, 1926-1940 (Box 7)
    - Grass Collection, 1960-1963 (Box 7)
    - Greenhouses
      - Guides to, 1960; undated (Box 7)
      - Plants of Special Interest (undated) (Box 7)
    - History/promotional material (Box 7)
    - Horner-McLaughlin Woods, plant lists and proposal, 1970; undated (Box 7)
    - Inventory (incomplete), 1920-1961; 3 folders (Box 7)
    - Logo (Box 7)
    - National Research Council-Biomedical Research Committee, 1983-1984 (Box 7)
    - Native Plant Protection, 1947 (Box 7)
    - New Developments, 10/79 (Box 7)
    - News Releases, 1969-1971; undated (Box 7)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - 1950-1972 (Box 7)
      - 1974-1985 (Box 7)
    - Nursery and Work Yard Construction, 1977-1978 (Box 7)
    - Organizational Chart and Job Descriptions, 1971; 1991 (Box 7)
    - Phenology Project, 1969-1971 (Box 7)
    - Poisonous Plants (Box 7)
    - Plant lists, 1965-1977 (Box 7)
    - Prairie Ecology, undated (Box 7)
    - Prominent Visitors
      - 1979-1985 (Box 7)
      - Visit of Chinese Paleobotanists, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Publicity, undated (Box 7)
    - Public Programs, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Radrick Forest, Preliminary Vascular Flora List, undated (Box 7)
    - Research Park, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Research Projects, 1967-1968 (Box 7)
    - Research Proposals, 1969-1983 (Box 7)
    - Sediment and Soil Analysis, 1958-1961 (Box 8)
    - Seed Exchange Lists, 1912-39 (Box 8)
    - Seventy-fifth Anniversary, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Seventy-fifth Anniversary-Printed Material (Box 8)
    - Tree on Dixboro Road removal issue), 1992-1994 (Box 8)
      (includes photographs)
    - United States Botanical Gardens, 1934-1946 (Box 8)
    - "Vegetation Survey in Detroit-Windsor Study Area,", 1954 (Box 8)
      (by A. G. Norman and E. Steiner)
    - Victory Gardens, 1944-1948 (Box 8)
    - Woody Plants Lists, 1967-1970; undated (Box 8)
  - 1928, 1951-2002
    - 75th Anniversary, 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - Adult Education, 1993 (Box 19)
    - Awards, 1997-1998 (Box 19)
    - Bonsai and Penjing Information Sheet (Box 19)
    - Bulletin, 1937 (Box 19)
    - Burn Restoration, 2002-2003 (Box 19)
    - Charles Fiore Nurseries, 1966 (Box 19)
    - Chestnuts, 1930; 1937 (Box 19)
    - Conservatory Visitor's Survey, 1985-1986 (Box 19)
    - Cotton Information Sheet, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Endangered Species Permit, 1999 (Box 19)
    - Endowment for Community Education (Box 19)
    - Environmental Concerns, 1999 (Box 19)
    - Environmental Education, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Flint Ink Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box 19)
    - Fontana Interview (Box 19)
    - Grass Collection (Box 19)
    - "Great American Gardens" on HGTV, 2001-2002 (Box 19)
    - Gypsy Moth Control, 2000 (Box 19)
    - History, 1957-1980 (Box 19)
    - Index Seminum, 1989-1990 (Box 19)
    - Information Sheet, 1978; 1991; 2001; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Insectivore Plant Labels (Box 19)
    - Koelz, Walter, 1989 (Box 19)
    - Landscape Heritage Education Workshop, 2002-2003 (Box 19)
    - Lists (Box 19)
    - Maps, 1929; 1951; 1955 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Plants in Danger, 1979 (Box 19)
    - Michigan Wildflower Association, 1941; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - National Museum Act, 1982-1983 (Box 19)
    - Nursery Inventory, 1960 (Box 19)
    - Plant Database, 1991-1996 (Box 19)
    - Plant Labels, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Plant List, 1954-1960 (Box 19)
    - Plant Tags, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Plat and Survey Maps (Box 19)
    - Prairie Plants, 2002 (Box 19)
    - Promotional Video, 1986 (Box 19)
    - Rhododendron Plants, 1975 (Box 19)
    - Sediment Distribution and Landform Classification, 1958 (Box 19)
    - Soils of Matthaei, 1997 (Box 19)
    - Southeast Michigan Naturists, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Student Testimonials, 1999 (Box 19)
    - Taylor, Sylvia (Box 19)
    - Topographical Maps (Folder 1)
    - Trees Native to Michigan, 1950 (Box 19)
    - UCAE Courses (University Courses in Adult Education), 1971-1972; 1979-1980; 1983 (Box 19)
    - UCUCA Inspection Research (University Committee on Use and Care of Animals), 1985-2002 (Box 19)
    - Wagner Collection (Box 19)
    - Wagner, Warren Obituary, 2000 (Box 19)
    - W.B. Chase Fellowship, 1995 (Box 19)
    - Weather Report, 1977-1985 (Box 19)
    - Website, 2001 (Box 19)
- Photographs and Scrapbooks (except Friends and Docents)
  The Photographs and Scrapbooks (except for Friends and Docents) series (1.5 linear feet) consists of photographs, negatives, matted photographs, and three scrapbooks containing photographs and newspaper clippings. The images represent grounds, buildings, and individuals. Of particular interest are photographs documenting daily operation and staff members at work, and those documenting special events such as the Auxiliary Pot Luck in 1967, and the A.G. Norman Memorial in 1987. Photographs and scrapbooks about either the Friends or Docents of Matthaei Botanical Gardens are listed under those groups' series. The series continues in Box 15.
  - Aerial Photographs (Box 8)
  - Auxiliary Pot Luck, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Benninghoff, Anne and Collins, William W. IV (Box 8)
    (Seed Collecting)
  - Christmas Lobby Decoration, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Conservatory one month after planting, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Education (Box 8)
  - Economic and Medicinal Garden, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Exhibits (Box 8)
  - Gleason, Henry A. (Box 8)
  - Grass Collection, 1979 (Box 8)
  - Greenhouses-Interiors (Box 8)
  - Grounds and Buildings (Box 8)
  - Individuals (unidentified) (Box 8)
  - Japanese Visitors (Box 8)
  - "Joy of Life" Exhibition of Artwork by Hanne Eske Dyva, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Laboratory (Box 8)
  - LaRue, Jane, Dedication of Memorial Sundial, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Matthaei By Moonlight, 2003; 2 optical disks CDs of .jpg's and printed thumbnails (Box 8)
  - Norman, A.G. and Kleinschmidt, Walter F., 1966 (Box 8)
  - Norman Memorial, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Pelton, Russell (Box 8)
  - Pots (Box 8)
  - Seventy-Fifth Anniversary Event, 1983; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Staff
    - Administrative, Individual Photos (Box 8)
    - Staff and Students (Box 8)
    - Group Picture, 1979; 1983 (Box 8)
  - Steere, William C. (Box 8)
  - Photographic Negatives
    - Buildings (Exterior and Interior) (Box 8)
    - Individuals (Box 8)
    - Norman Memorial, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Matted Photographs (staff and garden activities) (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1957-1984; 2 oversize volumes (Volume 1)
- Friends of Matthaei Botanical Gardens
  The Friends of Matthaei Botanical Gardens series, 1974-2002 (1.8 linear feet) is organized into two subseries: Administration and Organizational History. The Administration subseries consists of documents generated during the administrative and routine functions of the organization, such as agendas, minutes and correspondence. The Organizational History subseries comprises documents created or saved by the organization because they document the group's history. Of particular note are the organizational materials relating to the development of the Friends and scrapbooks of newspaper clippings about the Friends. This series continues in Box 14.
  - Administrative
    - Annual Reports, 1979; 1980 (Box 9)
    - Constitution and Revised By-Laws, 1974; 1979; 1983; 1985 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence and Memoranda, 1974; 1985; 1987; undated (Box 9)
    - Meetings, 1974-2001; 21 folders (Box 9)
    - Member and Officer Lists, 1982-1990; undated (Box 9)
    - Plant Sales
      - Price List, 1976 (Box 10)
      - Reports and Finances, 1992-1995; 2000-2002 (Box 10)
  - Organizational History
    - Histories (Box 10)
    - Organizational Efforts, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
    - Photographs of People and Events, 1982-1994 (Box 10)
    - Scrapbooks of Newspaper Clippings
      - 1974-1980, 1 oversize volumes (Volume 2)
      - 1981-1987, photocopied 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Loose newspaper clippings from scrapbooks (Box 10)
    - Signatures of Charter Members, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Tenth Anniversary Event Visitor List, 1984 (Box 10)
  - 25th Anniversary, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Board Meeting, 2002-2005 (Box 14)
  - Briarwood Certificate, 1980 (Box 14)
  - Bylaws (Box 14)
  - Charter Members, 1974 (Box 14)
  - Goals for Friends Board, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Guidelines for Board Members of Friends, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Herb Study Group, 2001-2004; undated (Box 14)
  - History, 1999-2005 (Box 14)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 14)
- Docents of Matthaei Botanical Gardens
  The Docents series, 1983-1997 (0.5 linear feet) documents the organization that was created in 1982 to train, manage and support docents at the gardens. The series includes mainly administrative documents generated by the organization, as well as a limited number of documents related to the history of the organization. Of particular note are a group of photographs that identify by name docents pictured performing their duties at the gardens.
  - Activities for Student Groups (Box 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1990-1997 (Box 10)
  - Bylaws and Working Rules, 1986-1994 (Box 10)
  - Continuing Education for Docents, 1983-1994 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence
    - 1983-1988 (Box 10)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 10)
      (received)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 10)
      (sent)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Financial Statements, 1987-1990 (Box 10)
  - Guide, undated; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - History (Box 10)
  - Meetings, 1983-1997; 8 folders (Box 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Photographs, 1986-1991 (Box 10)
  - Rosters, 1985-1997 (Box 10)
  - Schedules, 1989; 1995-1996 (Box 10)
- Events
  The Events series, 1987-2007 (0.4 linear feet) contains information related to the various programs sponsored by the Botanical Gardens. Of particular note is the information on the Ann Arbor Flower and Garden Show which comprises most of the series. Other events, such as Matthaei by Moonlight and the Gateway Garden Dedication, are also included in this series.
  - Admission Booth/Reciprocal Arboreta, Gardens, and Conservatories, 1993 (Box 13)
  - Alexandra "Sandy" Hicks Memoriam, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Ann Arbor Dance Works, 2003; 2007 (Box 13)
  - Blast to the Past (Box 13)
  - Calendar of Events, 1994 (Box 13)
  - Celebration of Light, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
  - Chocolate Day, 1998 (Box 13)
  - All Plant Sale, 1991; 1997-1998; 2001; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Flower and Garden Show
    - 1990-1993, 4 folders (Box 13)
    - 1994-1998, 5 folders (Box 14)
    - Clippings, 1939; 1990 (Box 14)
    - Demographics, 1992-1994 (Box 14)
    - History and Facts, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Mapping, 1994-1998 (Folder 2)
    - Planning Committee, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Planning Committee History, 1987-1990 (Box 14)
  - Gardening for Wildlife, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Gateway Garden Dedication, 1996 (Box 14)
  - George Washington Theme Tour, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Herb Fest, 1998-1999 (Box 14)
  - Matthaei by Moonlight, 1999-2003; 5 folders (Box 14)
  - Midsummer Gala, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Orientation., 1999 (Box 14)
  - Out of Africa, 1998-2001 (Box 14)
  - Pachysandra and English Ivy Giveaway (Box 14)
  - Sam Graham Trees Dedication, 1998 (Box 14)
  - Secret Garden Day, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Spring Perennial Sale, 1992-1996 (Box 14)
  - Spring Plant Sale, 1987-1991; 1999; 2001; 2004; 6 folders (Box 14)
  - Summer Events, 1999 (Box 14)
  - Virtual Botanical Garden Tour, 1997 (Box 14)
  - Wildflower Celebration, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Wildflower Day, 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Winter Lecture, 1994 (Box 14)
  - Workshop -- "Gardening with Children,", 1996 (Box 14)
- Photographs
  - Aerial Photographs, 6 folders (Box 15)
  - Aerial Photographs (oversize) (Folder 3)
    (located separately)
  - Aerial Photographs-Dixboro (Box 15)
  - Bartlett, H.H., 1912 (Box 15)
  - Bilon, Martin, 1918-1921 (Box 15)
  - Botanical Garden, 1905 (Box 15)
  - Chemistry Lab, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Conservatory Greenhouse Glazing Project, 2004 (Box 15)
  - Construction, 1962; 1965 (Box 15)
  - Construction -- 1st Phase, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Dedication Ceremony, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Desert House, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Dixboro Construction, 1959 (Box 15)
  - Dixboro Planning, 1962 (Box 15)
  - Environmental Chambers, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Greenhouse No. 2, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Greenhouse No. 3, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Grosse Pointe Exhibit (Box 15)
  - Kleinschmidt, Walter (Box 15)
  - Landscape, 1910 (Box 15)
  - Ludwig, John (Box 15)
  - Matted Photographs, 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Matthaei, Frederick, 1957 (Box 15)
  - Model Plan, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Mother's Day/Wildflower Day, 1996 (Box 15)
  - Norman, A. Geoffrey, 1962 (Box 15)
  - People in the Garden (Box 15)
  - Plat Map, 1908 (Box 15)
  - Site View (Box 15)
  - Staff, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Students and Staff, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Sundial Dedication, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Temperate House (Box 15)
  - Tropical House, 1966 (Box 15)
  - Willow Pond, 1966 (Box 15)
- Plans
  The Plans series, 1923-2004 (2 linear feet) contains specific information relating to various parts of the Gardens. These site plans cover the purchase and development of the Dixboro Site, the development of Fleming Creek, and other plans revolving around renovations pertaining to specific properties owned by the Gardens. These plans also cover the development of specific garden plots and themed plant beds located in the Gardens, such as the Labyrinth Garden and the Gateway Garden.
  - Azary Rock Garden, 1996-2001 (Box 15)
  - Constructed Wet, 1994-2001 (Box 15)
  - Development Plan maps (Folder 4)
  - Dixboro Site
    - General, 1967 (Box 15)
    - Bridges, 1997 (Box 15)
    - Construction, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
    - Deed History, 1957 (Box 15)
    - History, 1957-2001 (Box 15)
    - Maps (oversize), 1 folders (Folder 5)
    - Ownership History, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Dix Pond Planting, 1983 (Box 15)
  - East Boundary, 1923 (Box 15)
  - Fleming Creek
    - General, 1975-1981 (Box 15)
    - Data, 1970 (Box 15)
    - Habitats and Plants, 1997-1999 (Box 15)
    - Rubble Removal, 1993 (Box 15)
  - Formal Gardens Campaign, 1999-2000 (Box 15)
  - Front Entrance, Lower Level Garden, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Front Shack Garden, 1991-1993; 1996 (Box 16)
  - Gateway Garden, 1997-1999 (Box 16)
  - Gateway Garden Annuals, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Gateway Garden Pavilion, 1996-1999 (Box 16)
  - General, 1958-1961; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Genetics Garden, 1961 (Box 16)
  - Golf Course, 1997 (Box 16)
  - Grape Walk, 1926-1928 (Box 16)
  - Greenhouse (Box 16)
  - Herb Knot Garden, 1994; 1997 (Box 16)
  - Horner -- McLaughlin Woods Checklist of Woody Plants (Box 16)
  - Horner's Woods and Michigan Botany Club, 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - House Plans (Box 16)
  - Inglis House Grounds, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Jane LaRue Memorial Sundial, 1984-1986 (Box 16)
  - John Dix Field, 1968 (Box 16)
  - Labyrinth Garden, 2003-2004 (Box 16)
  - Labyrinth Garden Maps (Box 16)
  - Land Gifts, 2002 (Box 16)
  - McLaughlin Woods-Pelton Track, 1955-1983 (Box 16)
  - Medicinal Garden (Box 16)
  - Narcissus Culture Project (Box 16)
  - New Site for Gardens, 1957 (Box 16)
  - Old Botanical Garden, 1931; 1940 (Box 16)
  - Oval Garden, 1926-1929; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Parker Brook Pond, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Perennial Nursery (Box 16)
  - Perennial and Rose Garden, 1999 (Box 16)
  - Plants at Gardens, Horner, and McLaughlin Woods, 1965-1971 (Box 16)
  - Prairie Site
    - Establishment Article, 1970 (Box 16)
    - History and Establishment, 1967-1972 (Box 16)
    - Minutes and Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 16)
    - Reference Materials, 1988-2002 (Box 16)
  - Radrick Bog and Forest Property, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
  - Radrick Fen, 1999 (Box 17)
  - Radrick Woods (Box 17)
  - Regent's Purchase of Land Deeds, 1954-1973 (Box 17)
  - Rock Garden, 1927 (Box 17)
  - Rose Collection (Box 17)
  - Sam Graham Trees Development, 1992-1998 (Box 17)
  - Sam Graham Woods, 1995-1997 (Box 17)
  - Shade Garden, 1992-1995 (Box 17)
  - Site Views, 1987 (Box 17)
  - South Ditch Data, 1928 (Box 17)
  - Trail to Parker Hill, 2002-2003 (Box 17)
  - Tree and Shrub Planting, 1992 (Box 17)
  - Virginia Bailey Collection, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Woodland Wildflower Garden
    - Undated (Box 17)
    - 1958-1970, 1985-1989; 1999; 2003; 8 folders (Box 17)
    - History (Box 17)
    - Master Coordinator, 1985-1988 (Box 17)
    - Officer Responsibilities, 1986-1989 (Box 17)
    - Sunny Native Wildflowers, 1986-1990 (Box 17)
    - Trail Tips, 1980 (Box 17)
    - Volunteer Information, 1988-1989 (Box 17)
    - Wildflower Beds 1-6, 1986-1990; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Wildflowers of the Great Lakes Region, 2000 (Box 17)
    - Wildflowers of the Southern Great Lakes, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Workgroup (Box 17)
- Projects
  The Projects series, 1961-2002 (0.5 linear feet) contains information on broader construction projects compared to the Plans series. This includes the construction of the Friends Pavilion, the renovation of the inside of the conservatory, the plans for repairing the damage done to the gardens by storms, and the creation of the Hot Line for Poisonous Plants.
  - Addition, 1963-1965 (Box 17)
  - Candidate Plants (Box 17)
  - Conservatory, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Conservatory Renovation, 1994-2002 (Box 17)
  - East Addition, 1963-1966 (Box 17)
  - Evergreen Plantings (Box 17)
  - Experimental Solar Greenhouse, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Friends Pavilion (Box 17)
  - Front Gate Renovation, 1996 (Box 17)
  - Garden Construction, 1990-1993 (Box 17)
  - Grant Proposals, 1992; 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Horticulture Therapy Training Project, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Hot Line for Poisonous Plants, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Irrigation, 1984; 1994 (Box 17)
  - Labor Proposal, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Lobby Renovation, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
  - Phenology Project, 1996 (Box 17)
  - Plant Research Center, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Plants to Move, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Storm Damage Repair, 1980-1984 (Box 18)
  - Swan Creek Watershed, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Trail Improvement, 2000 (Box 18)
  - Unrealized Projects (Box 18)
- Research
  The Research series, 1959-2004 (0.7 linear feet) contains information on various research projects done at the Botanical Gardens. Included is information from various biology and botany classes that researched the gardens as well as personal research projects done by people outside of the university. Personal research topics are organized alphabetically by the name of the researcher.
  - Barnes, Burton, 1966-1999 (Box 18)
  - Biology 351, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Biology 381, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Botany, 125, 172, 572 (Box 18)
  - Botany, 351 and 572 (Box 18)
  - Contiguous Plots Data, 1974 (Box 18)
  - Dix Field Study, 1966-1967; 1970 (Box 18)
  - Emerald Ash Borer, 2004 (Box 18)
  - Facility Usage, 1992-1997 (Box 18)
  - General, 1994-2009; 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Hershock, Chad, 1998-1999 (Box 18)
  - Lab Reports, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Petri, Jana, 2004 (Box 18)
  - Phytometer Data, 1967-1969; 1971; 5 folders (Box 18)
  - Plant Competition Experiment, 1967 (Box 18)
  - Plants and German History, 2003-2004 (Box 18)
  - Research Personnel, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Research Requirements, 1959-1960 (Box 18)
  - Soils and Soils Tests, 1977-1979 (Box 18)
  - Water Quality Study, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Wildflower Research Project, 1989 (Box 18)
- Audio-Visual Material
  The Audio-Visual Material series, 1985-2003 (2 linear feet) contains primarily videocassette tapes, but also audiocassettes. Most of the material is from various years of the Ann Arbor Flower and Garden Show. Also included is a videocassette containing the episode of HGTV's Great American Gardens that featured the Matthaei Botanical Gardens.
  - Audiocassettes
    - Flower and Garden Show, undated (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1992 (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show: A Walk on the Wild Side, 1993 (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Matthaei Botanical Gardens, 1991 (Box 20)
  - Videocassettes
    - An Adventure in Learning, 1986 (Box 20)
    - Botanical Gardens slide transfer, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, undated (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show commercial, 1990; 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1991 (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1992 (Box 20)
    - Flower and Garden Show, 1995 (Box 20)
    - For Your Information (Box 20)
    - Grosse Pointe War Memorial, Points of Horticulture, 2003; 4 tapes (Box 20)
    - HGTV "Great American Gardens," Show #105, 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Ken Bolling, EMU, Andrew Gecsey, Lucy Liggit (Box 20)
    - Leaders and Best '90 (Box 20)
    - Living in the Lakes Area -- Tour of the Matthaei Botanical Gardens (Box 20)
    - Matthaei Botanical Gardens, Part I and II (Box 20)
    - Michigan Forum, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Secret Garden, Part I and II, 2 tapes (Box 20)
    - Sencon Greenhouse (Box 20)
    - To Make a Prairie: A History of Prairie Establishment at the University of Michigan's Matthaei Botanical Gardens, 1989 (Box 20)
    - Wildflower Garden Dedication, 1991 (Box 20)